Phew, we made it...
（井藤ノノハ）間に合って　よかった。
There's no puzzle I can't solve. We're moving on!
（大門カイト）
俺に解けないパズルは　ねえ。
次　行くぞ！
え？　あっ　ちょっと…。
Hey! Let's catch our breathe at least!
休もうよ～！
I'm gonna defeat Orpheus,
心の声
俺は必ず　オルペウスを倒す。
そして　ジンを取り戻す！
and take Jin back!
（レイツェル）
ようこそ　アムギーネ共和国へ。→
Welcome to the republic of Amgine.
君たちを
国賓として歓迎するそうよ。
You will be treated as guests of the state.
（逆之上ギャモン）
エニグマ大統領の代理とは→
So now you're president Enigma's deputy?
いつの間にやら
随分と偉くなったもんだな。
Climbing that rank ladder quite fast, are we?
（姫川エレナ）
せっかく迎えに来てくれたのに→
Come on, she came to pick up us. Don't be such a jerk.
そんな嫌み言う事ないじゃない。
（レイツェル）フン。
（ギャモン）アントワネット。　ついて来んのは
認めたが　観光じゃねえからな。
Antoinette, I let you come along, but remember we're not here for sightseeing.
アムギーネ行きのチケット取ったのは
私だって事　お忘れなく。
And remember that I was the one who paid for the flight.
（ギャモン）
ああ　そうだな。　ありがとよ。
Right. Thanks.
（エレナ）ふ～ん　悪くないわね。
This isn't half bad.
夕食は　５時よ。→
Dinner's at five.
寝室は
それぞれに用意してあるわ。
You have your separate bedrooms.
着替えは　こっちよ。
You can use this room for changing.
お好きなものを　どうぞ。
Pick whatever is to your liking.
へぇ…　私のも　あるのね。
There's some for me too?
何の事はねえ。　俺たちが来る事は
お見通しだったらしいな。
What's so surprising? Apparently our arrival was on their schedules before it was on ours.
聞こえるか！　真方ジン！
いや…　オルペウス！
Can you hear me, Makata Jin?
I mean, Orpheus!
俺が　ここに来た目的も
とっくに分かってんだろ！
You know already why I'm here, don't you?
だったら　もったいつけずに
出てこい！→
Then stop wasting our time and come on out!
Let's get this crap over with!
さっさと始めようぜ！
（エレナ）ガリレオ…。
Galileo...
では　また夕食で。
迎えをよこすわ。
See you at dinner then.
I'll send someone to pick you up.
（ギャモン）レイツェル。
Raetsel...
カイトは　てめえの事を心配してたぜ。
こうなっちまってもな。
Kaito was worried about you. Even at this point.
You should focus on worrying about yourselves.
自分の心配をする事ね。
（モニター・真方ジン）
「あの男の意欲は買おう。→
Let's do as he asked.
およそ　大門カイトの足元にも
及ばぬがな」。
He couldn't even reach the point where Daimon Kaito is standing.
（軸川ソウジ）
ギャモン君が　アムギーネ共和国に!?
Gammon's in Amgine?
Yeah. Look at this.
（ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド）
ああ。　これを見てくれ。
（ビショップ）アムギーネ便に搭乗した事は
確認がとれています。
It's certain that they boarded an Amgine flight.
エレナ君まで…　この非常時に！
Even Elena?
Why would they go there at such a grave time?
レイツェルからのメッセージを
彼も聞いていた。
He heard the message from Raetsel as well.
（モニター・レイツェル）「ジンを救う
回想
方法が１つだけ　ある」。
But there is only one way to save him.
何だよ　それ!?
（レイツェル）「私　カイト　ルーク　フリーセル→
What?
Me, Kaito, Rook, Freecell, or Gammon.
そして　ギャモン。→
この中の誰かが
ファイ・ブレインとして覚醒し→
One of us must awaken as a Phi Brain and offer our brain to Orpheus.
その頭脳を器として
オルペウスに　ささげる事。→
そうすれば　ジンは解放されるわ」。
Then Jin would be freed.
まさか…
候補として名前が挙がった事で→
Are you telling me
that he thought he'd become the Phi Brain because his name was listed too?
ファイ・ブレインになろうと
暴走を始めたのでは…。
いや　彼に限って
それは　ありえない。
No, that's not something he'd do.
ええ。　恐らく　ギャモン君は→
Yeah. He's probably trying to serve as a shield for Kaito.
カイト君の盾になろうと
しているのでしょう。
まったく…
ガリレオらしいな。
So typical of Galileo.
But even if that's the case, at his current level, it's too much of a risky bet!
しかし…　だとしても→
今のギャモン君の実力では
危険な賭けすぎる。
下手をすれば
命取りになりかねない。
It might even cost him his life.
一体　どんな勝算があって…。
What on earth is going on in his mind?
しばらくは
様子を見るしかなさそうだね。
For now, we've got no choice but to watch.
（ギャモン）んがっ…　んぐ…　はむっ…。
お味は　どう？
How is it?
うまいぜ。　文句のつけようが
ないくらいにな。
Tastes great.
I couldn't find anything to complain about even if I wanted to.
だが　こんな茶番は　どうでもいい。
But this is just a farce and you know it.
俺は　オルペウスに会いに来たんだ！
I'm here to face Orpheus!
その割に　よく食べるわね。
You say that and eat like a starved wolf.
（ギャモン）腹が減っては何とやら。
お代わりだ！
Hunger's good for nothing! Seconds!
（ジン）随分と威勢がいいな。
You sure seem quite spirited.
Jin!
（レイツェル）ジン！
オルペウス！　てめえ！
Orpheus, you bitch!
レディー同伴とは余裕だな。
Accompanied by a lady, huh? Taking it easy, I see?
アントワネットは関係ねえ。
そんな事より　パズルだ！→
Antoinette's none of your business. Puzzling with me is though!
俺を指名したのは　てめえだろ！
さっさと　パズルを用意しろ！
You called me out, didn't you?
Get that puzzle ready!
そう慌てるな。
候補には選んでやったが→
Don't be in such a hurry.
I did pick you as a potential vessel,
所詮　お前は
大門カイトの足元にも及ばない。
but you're close to nothing when compared to Daimon Kaito.
俺は　誰にも負けちゃいねえ！→
I don't lose to anyone!
その事を証明してやるよ。
I, Sakanoue Gammon, will prove that to you here and now!
この　逆之上ギャモン様が
今　ここでな！
ちょっと　ガリレオ　落ち着いてよ。
Galileo, calm down...
うるせえ！　邪魔すんな！
Shut up! Don't get in the way!
フッ。　レイツェル　よかったな。
Isn't this great, Raetsel?
お前のジンを　思ったよりも早く
取り戻せるかもしれない。→
You might get to meet your beloved Jin sooner than expected.
この男と　引き換えにな。
In exchange for him, that is.
では　逆之上ギャモン
お前の望み　かなえてやろう。
Well then, Sakanoue Gammon.
Let me give you what you want.
こ…　ここは…。
What?
どわっ!?
Welcome, Sakanoue Gammon.
（ジン）ようこそ　逆之上ギャモン。
オルペウスの腕輪が眠る　賢者のパズルへ。
This is a Sage Puzzle where an Orpheus Armlet sleeps.
あんた　やっぱり…。
Are you serious?!
（ジン）
砂時計の砂が　全て落ちる前に
最上階のゴールまで行け。→
Get to the goal on the top level before the hourglass runs out.
さもないと　全ては消滅し
待っているのは　奈落の底だ。
Otherwise, everything will perish and the abyss will swallow you.
（ギャモン）挑戦するのは　俺一人だ！
I'm the one challenging you here! Don't involve her!
こいつは関係ねえ！
ここから出せ！
Let her out of here!
（ジン）もう遅い。→
Too late.
それに　賭ける命は
１つより２つの方が　興も乗る。
Not to mention, betting two lives instead of one is more exciting.
てめえ！　汚えぞ！
That's not fair, you asshole!
いいわよ　私は。
な…　何だと!?
It's okay.
What?!
ガリレオ…　あんた　腕輪をつけて→
Galileo, you want to put on an Armlet and become the Phi Brain before anyone else...
誰よりも早く
ファイ・ブレインになるつもりでしょ。
大門カイトを守るために。
（ギャモン）うっ…。
to protect Daimon Kaito.
なら　私は　そんなあんたの覚悟を
見届けてあげるわ。
Then I'll see your determination through to the end!
な…　何　考えてやがる！→
Are you nuts? You could die here, you know!
下手すりゃ
命が　なくなるんだぞ!?
Of course I know.
そんな事　分かってる。
分かってねえ！
I doubt you do!
あのね…　あんたが　ガリレオなら
私は　アントワネットよ。
You're Galileo, but I'm Antoinette.
命の１つや２つ→
I'm not the type to have regrets about trusting puzzle maniacs with a few lives.
パズルバカの誰かさんに預けて
後悔すると思う？→
こうなった以上　最後まで
見届けさせてもらうから。
Now that it's come to this, I'm gonna see it through the end!
お前…。
You...
（ジン）いいのか？
パズルは既に始まっているぞ。
I don't mean to interrupt, but the puzzle's already started.
Shit!
くそっ！
（ギャモン）
パネルの色が分かれてるって事は→
The panel colors are different. That means they move in different ways.
動きが違う事を
示してるはずだ。→
だとしたら…。
動いた！
スライドパズルね。
It moved! It's a slide puzzle.
（ギャモン）次は　緑のパネルだ。
A green's next.
（エレナ）砂時計から見て
青が縦方向に→
So from the hourglass's point of view, the blue is vertical, and green is horizontal movement.
緑は横方向に動くって事ね。
そういうこった。
That's it.
足元には気を付けろよ。
落ちたら　一巻の終わりだ。
Watch your feet. If you fall, that's game over.
パズルタイムの始まりだ！
It's puzzle time!
（エレナ）青いパネルは縦　緑のパネルは横
という事は→
Blue panels move vertically, and green moves horizontally.
Which means if we want to go up a level...
上のフロアに上がるためには…。
赤だ。→
We need reds.
行くぞ！
Ready?
思ったとおりだ！
Just as I thought!
（エレナ）どうしたの？
上へ行くには赤でしょ。
What's wrong? Don't we need red to go up?
（ギャモン）だが　それじゃ
行き止まりになっちまう。
Yeah, but using that would lead us to a dead end.
This way!
こっちだ！
心の声
（エレナ）やっぱり
本気のガリレオは　すごいわ。
When he's serious, he's really awesome!
やるじゃない。
Not half bad! We're winning easily!
楽勝ね！
ケッ　気持ち悪ぃぜ。
You can't believe how creepy it is.
何よ！
せっかく褒めてあげたのに。
What? I just praised you!
このパズルがだ。
えっ？
I meant this puzzle.
（ギャモン）ここまで来れば
簡単に　ゴールまで見通せる。→
Everything up until now has been too obvious.
あの赤いパネルに移って
４階まで上がれば…→
If we go up to the top floor using that red panel,
ゴールだ。　他に道はねえ。
それの何が悪いのよ。
we'll be at the goal.
There's no other way.
What's the problem with that?
よし　行こう！
Let's just go!
フン…　たわいもない。
That's a goner.
あっ!?
な…　何!?
What?
What's going on?
（エレナ）
ちょ…　ちょっと　何よ　これ！
とんだ仕掛けが
してあったぜ。
This is insane!
だけど　赤いパネルが上に行くか
下に行くか分からずに→
But how can we get to the goal if we don't know which way the red panels will move?
どうやって　ゴールまで…。
どわ!?
あっ！
So we're back to zero now?
（ギャモン）振り出しに戻るってか。
（ギャモン）どうなってる…？
What's going on?
どう行っても
行き止まりじゃねえか。
It's a dead end both ways.
That can't be!
（エレナ）そ…　そんな！
さあ　どうする？　逆之上ギャモン。
What do you do now, Sakanoue Gammon?
What should we do now?
一体　どうしたらいいの…。
Don't move.
（ギャモン）動くな。
えっ？
どういう事？
パズルには　必ず答えがある。
What's going on?
Every puzzle has a solution.
勝負は　これからだぜ！
The fun starts now!
（エレナ）ガリレオ！　時間が…。
（ギャモン）分かってる！
Galileo! We're running out of time!
I know!
We're going a different way this time.
（ギャモン）
さっきとは別のルートを通るぜ。
（エレナ）やった！　最上階よ！
We did it! We're at the top!
（ギャモン）喜ぶのは　まだ早ぇ。
（エレナ）え？
Too early to celebrate.
Wait, what?
（エレナ）これって…。
（ギャモン）ああ。→
Yeah. There's no way to the goal.
ゴールへ行くルートが見当たらねえ…。→
どういう事だ!?
What's going on?
心の声
（エレナ）これは　ガリレオの戦い。→
This is Galileo's fight. I can only watch.
私には見ている事しかできない。→
いいえ…　助けたくても
私には答えが分からない。
But even if I wanted to help, I couldn't.
もはや　これまでか。
Is that it?
やるだけ無駄だったな。→
What a waste.
あとは　奈落の底で　永遠に
そのレディーと慰め合うがいい。
Enjoy your eternity in the abyss with your lady.
ふざけんな！
Drop dead, asshole!
てめえなんかの思いどおりに
させてたまるか！
I'm not gonna let you have your way!
俺は絶対　諦めねえ！
I'm never gonna give up!
To reach the blue that leads to the goal,
（ギャモン）ゴールへ向かう
青のパネルに乗るためには→
３階から行くしかねえ。→
we'd need to go back down to the third level.
だが…
３階のルートは　つながってねえ。
But the route doesn't connect there.
心の声
（ギャモン）どうすりゃ
ゴールに　つながる？→
How can we reach the goal?
あのパネルは何だ？
動かねえパネルが　なぜ並んでる？
Wait, what's that panel?
Why are there two of the same color?
あれに何かが　ある。
There's something going on there.
それっきゃ
このパズルを解く方法は　ねえ！
There's no other way to solve this puzzle!
行くぞ　エレナ！
あ…。
Let's do this, Elena!
分かった。
私は…　ギャモン　あなたを信じる！
Fine.
I'll trust you, Gammon!
That's right! I'm Galileo, Sakanoue Gammon!
そうだ　俺は
ガリレオの　逆之上ギャモン様だ！
I get it now.
そういう事かよ。
This way!
こっちだ！
Hurry up!
急げ！
Quickly!
早く早く。
Jump!
跳べ～！
オルペウスの腕輪!?
An Orpheus Armlet?!
うぐっ…　うわぁ～！→
ギャモン！
あ…。
Gammon!
まさか…
腕輪に　のみ込まれたの!?
Are you telling me you lost to the Armlet?!
おめでとう。　これで望みどおり→
Congratulations.
Now you got what Daimon Kaito did, just as you wished.
お前も　大門カイトと同じものを
手に入れたというわけだ。→
だが　やはり　私の見たとおりの
未来が訪れたな。
However, the future I saw has caught up to you.
No way!
そんな…　うそよ！
Dream on!
バカ言ってんじゃねえよ！
Are you nuts or what?
俺は　カイトなんかより
はるかに　すげえんだよ！
I'm a thousand times more awesome than Kaito!
ほぅ…　面白い。
Amusing.
As soon as Daimon Kaito gets involved, the future goes into a chaotic swirl.
大門カイトが関わると
未来が　途端に揺らぐ。
ケッ！　いつまでも　ほざいてろ。
Go cry in a corner about it.
あっ　ちょっと　ギャモン！
Wait, Gammon!
心の声
（ジン）だが　どう揺らごうと…。
But it doesn't matter how much it swirls.
This is what you get for messing with me.
ま　俺にかかりゃあ　こんなもんさ。
見届けるってほどの事もねえ。
You didn't even have to "see it through."
ん…　ああ？　どうした？
What's wrong?
Elena?
エレナ？
うっ…。
どわっ!?→
な…　何だ？　いきなり。
What's gotten into you?
バカ！　バカ　バカ　バカ！
Stupid! Stupid!
心配ばかりさせんじゃないわよ！
Don't make me worry about you so much, you idiot!
この大バカ！
（エレナ）
見てるしか…　できなかったの…。
I could do nothing but watch...
私…　見てるしか…。　ごめん。
I could only watch... Sorry.
見ててくれたから　解けたんだろ。
I could only solve it because you were watching.
ねえ　さっき　初めて
ちゃんと名前で呼んでくれたよね。
Hey, earlier you called me by my name for the first time, didn't you?
あぁ？　呼んだっけ？　フッ。
Did I? Hmm...
バカ～！
Jerk!
（ギャモン）これは…。
（エレナ）どうかした？
What's...
Is something wrong?
心の声
（ギャモン）これは何だ？
What is this?
Gammon? Gammon!
ギャモン？　ギャモン？→
ギャモン…　ギャモン！
Gammon!
Preview
Excuse me for interrupting with a lame little problem.
Doubt, let's say there's a stairway in front of you.